Guide to the Sino-Japanese and Russo-Japanese War Prints Collection 10142303
C. V. Starr East Asian Library
Sino-Japanese and Russo-Japanese War Prints Collection
1864-1904
1894-1895
1904
C. V. Starr East Asian Library
Adler, Allen R.
Adler, Frances Beatty
Swann Galleries
10142303
3 Linear Feet 110 prints in 1 mapcase drawer
The Sino-Japanese and Russo-Japanese War Prints Collection (Nisshin Nichi-Ro sensō nishikie; 日清・日露戦争錦絵) is a collection of 110 nishikie prints by various late 19th Century Japanese ukiyo-e artists depicting events during the First Sino-Japanese War and the Russo-Japanese War, as well as other events, dating from 1864-1904.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject. Arranged alphabetically by the Romanized titles of the prints within each series.
Biographical / Historical
The First Sino-Japanese War was fought between China and Japan from 1894 to 1895 over territorial control of Korea, Manchuria, Taiwan, and the Yellow Sea. Japan won the war and gain control of Korea, Taiwan, and the Liaodong Peninsula.
The Russo-Japanese War was fought between Russia and Japan from 1904 to 1905 over Manchuria and Korea. Major battles took place in Liaodong province and Mukden, as well as the seas around Japan, Korea, and China. Japan won the war and Russia cedes the Guandong Leased Territory and South Sakhalin to Japan.
Scope and Contents
The Sino-Japanese and Russo-Japanese War Prints Collection (Nisshin Nichi-Ro sensō nishikie; 日清・日露戦争錦絵) consists of 110 nishikie prints that document the events during the First Sino-Japanese War and the Russo-Japanese War, as well as other events, dating from 1864-1904. Most of the prints were created by various late 19th Century Japanese ukiyo-e artists and mostly published in Tokyo, Japan.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The bulk of the collection (108 prints, item 1-108) was donated, in 2008, by Alan R. Adler and Frances Beatty Adler. Four additional prints were later purchased by auction from Swann Galleries, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is located off-site.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection has no restrictions.
Related Materials
Similar collections with online contents can be found in various online databases:
Cultural Japan. Link
日清戦争錦絵美術館. Link
NDLデジタル化資料. Link
野田市立図書館所蔵資料. Link
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. Contact starr@library.columbia.edu for more information.
color woodcuts (prints); Color prints, Japanese -- Meiji period, 1868-1912; Sino-Japanese War, 1894-1895; Sino-Japanese War, 1894-1895; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905 -- Pictorial works; Ukiyoe; Yalu River (China and Korea); Inch'ŏn (Korea); P'yŏngyang (Korea); Yellow River (China); Adler, Allen R.; Adler, Frances Beatty; Swann Galleries; Utagawa, Kuniteru, 1830?-1874; Utagawa, Kunimasa, 1848-1920; Hiroshige, III, 1842?-1894; Mizuno, Toshikata, 1866-1908; Utagawa, Yoshitora, active 1850-1870; Taguchi, Yonesaku, 1864-1903; Kobayashi, Kiyochika, 1847-1915; Hashimoto, Chikanobu, 1838-1912; Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920; Adachi, Ginkō, active 1870-1900
- Series I: Sino-Japanese War Prints/日清戦争錦絵, 1894-1895
  - 安城渡激戦之図 = Anjō no Watash gekisen no zu = A Fierce Battle at Anjo Ferry, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 001)
    Scope and Contents
    絵師/Artist: 円活 Enkatsu. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Yokoyama Ryōhachi. 出版者: 横山良八.
  - 安城渡大激戦松崎大尉勇猛 = Anjōto daigekisen Matsuzaki Taii yūmō = Brave Captain Matsuzaki during a Fierce Battle at Anjo Ferry, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 002)
    絵師/Artist: 年方 Toshikata. Full name: 水野年方 Mizuno, Toshikata, 1866-1908. Published: Tokyo, Japan.
  - 朝鮮電報 = Chōsen denpō = A Telegraph from Korea, 明治27, Meji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 003)
    絵師/Artist: 作者不詳 Artist Unknown. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Yamamoto Yoichi. 出版者: 山本与市.
  - 朝鮮事件日清大激戦之圖 第二 = Chōsen jiken Nisshin daigekisen no zu. Dai ni = A Fierce Fighting between Japan and China During the 1882 Incident in Korea, 明治27, Meij 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 004)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Ozeki Iwao. 出版者: 内務省検閲済; 臨写印刷兼発行者 尾関岩吉 日本橋区若松町十五番地.
  - 朝鮮京城之小戦 = Chōsen Keijō no shōsen = A Skirmish at Seoul, 明治27, Meij 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 005)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan.
  - 第一征清軍九連城掩撃中 = Daiichi Seiseigun Kurenjō engekichū = A Surprise Attack of the Kiuliencheng Fortress by the First Conquering China Troop, 明治27, Meij 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 006)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助.
  - 大孤山沖海洋島ニ日本海軍清艦ヲ撃沈ス = Daikosan-oki Kaiyōtō ni Nihon Kaibun Shin kan o gekichin su = The Japanese Navy Destroys Chinese Warships in Haiyangtao Off Takushan, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 007)
    絵師/Artist: 年光 Toshimitsu. Full name: 進斎年光 Shinsai, Toshimitsu. Geographical Subject: 大孤山 Dagu Mountain
  - 大日本陸軍牙山大勝利 = Dai Nihon Rikugun Gazan daishōri = Great Victory of Japanese Forces at Gazan, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 008)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Sawa Kyūjirō. 出版者: 澤久次郎.
  - 大日本ト清国ト両軍平城激戦圖 = Dai Nihon to Shinkoku to ryōrun Heijō gekisenzu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 009)
    絵師/Artist: 楳堂小国政 Baidō Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Katada Chōjirō. 出版者: 片田長治郎.
  - 第二師団長佐久間中尉栄城府占領ノ圖 = Daini shidan-chō Sakuma Chūi Eijō-fu senryō no zu, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 010)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉.
  - 蓋平占領之圖 = Gaihei senryō no zu, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 011)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助.
  - 元山行進日清両軍平壌大激戦之図 = Genzan kōshin Nisshin ryōrun Heijō daigekisen no zu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 012)
    絵師/Artist: 秋香 Shūka. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Sekiguchi Masajirō. 出版者: 関口政治郎.
  - 牛荘城外之激戦 = Gyūsō jōgai no gekisen, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 013)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925.
  - 平壌激戦玄武門攻撃の際、清兵嶮に拠りて、善く防御し、日軍頗る苦戦す時に一勇兵あり、城壁を乗り越え、ついに開門大勝を得て、古今の大功を顕す。比人は誰そ。三河国の住人歩兵一等兵原田重吉氏則是なり = Heijō gekisen Genbumon kōgeki..., 明治27, Meji 27 [1894]; 2 copies (Mapcase A5, Item 014-015)
    絵師/Artist: 年方 Toshikata. Full name: 水野年方 Mizuno, Toshikata, 1866-1908. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Sekiguchi Masajirō. 出版者: 関口政治郎.
  - 平壌激戦四圍進撃圖 = Heijō gekisen shishū shingekizu = A Situation of the Fierce Battle in Pyongyang, 明治27年10月, Meiji 27 [1894 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 016)
    絵師/Artist: 延保 Nobuyasu. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Naraha Shūhei. 出版者: 楢葉周平.
  - 平城玄武門兵士先登之圖 = Heijō gekisen Genbumon heishi sentō no zu = The First Climber up a Pyongyang Gate, 明治27年10月, Meiji 27 [1894 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 017)
    絵師/Artist: 米作 Beisaku. Full name: 田口米作 Taguchi, Beisaku, 1864-1903. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Inoue Kichijirō. 出版者: 井上吉次郎.
  - 平壌之激戦我軍大勝利之図 = Heijō no gekisen waga gun daishōri no zu= Japan's Great Victory from the Fierce Fight in Pyongyang, [明治27年頃], circa Meiji 27 [circa 1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 018)
    絵師/Artist: 安達吟光 Adachi Ginkō. Also known as: 安達平七 Adachi, Heishichi. [出版者不明], [出版地不明] 日清戦役錦絵帖.
  - 奉天府附近戦闘 = Hōten-fu fukin sentō = A Battle in the Neighbourhood of Mukden, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894]; 2 copies (Mapcase A5, Item 019-020)
    絵師/Artist: 楳堂小国政 Baidō Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Kumajiro. 出版者: 福田熊次郎.
  - 威海衛 廿八年一月 … = Ikaiei. Nijūhachinen Ichigatsu … = The Battle at Weihaiwei, in January Meiji 28 [1895], 明治28年2月, Meiji 28 [1895 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 021-022)
  - 威海衛海軍攻撃之図 = Ikaiei Kaigun kōgeki no zu = Navy Attack at WeihaiWei, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 023-024)
    絵師/Artist: 延保 Nobuyasu. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Morita Hikojirō. 出版者: 森田彦治郎.
  - 威海衛陸海攻撃之図 = Ikaiei Kaigun kōgeki no zu = Navy Attack at WeihaiWei, 明治27年2月12日, Meji 27 [1894 February 12] (Mapcase A5, Item 024)
    絵師/Artist: 年章 Toshiaki. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉.
  - 威海衛陸戦百尺崖所之激闘 = Ikaiei Rikusen hyakushaku gaisho no gekitō = A Fierce Battle at the "Hundred-Foot-Cliff" Fortress near Weihaiwei, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 025)
  - 威海衛斥候隊ノ奮戦陸軍歩兵中尉 守永直一氏 大敵追テ四面ヲ囲ム憤励シ部下督ス弾丸雨注ヘ突入シテ遂ニ名誉ノ戦死ヲ為ス = Ikaiei sekkōtai no funsen. Rikugun hohei chūi ... = Japanese Reconnaissance Troop Bravely Fights near Weihaiwei, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 026)
    絵師/Artist: 安達吟光 Adachi Ginkō. Also known as: 安達平七 Adachi, Heishichi. Published: Tokyo, Japan.
  - 今景季 = Ima Kagesue = Present Kagesue [Kajiwara], the First Climber of the Enemy Fortress, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895]; 2 copies (Mapcase A5, Item 027-028)
    絵師/Artist: 年方 Toshikata Full name: 水野年方 Mizuno, Toshikata, 1866-1908.
  - 樺山軍令部長西京丸を以て敵艦に当る= Kabayama Gunshirei Buchō Saikyōmaru o motte tekikan ni ataru = Kabayama, Head of the Military Command Department, Attacks, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 029)
    絵師/Artist: 安達吟光 Adachi Ginkō. Also known as: 安達平七 Adachi, Heishichi. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Kumajiro. 出版者: 福田熊次郎.
  - 海軍将校等征清の戦略議論する図 = Kaigun shōkō nado sei-Shin no senryaku giron suru zu, 明治27年9月, Meiji 27 [1894 September]; 3 copies (Mapcase A5, Item 030)
  - 海洋嶋附近激戦：九月廿日号外 = Kaiyōtō fukin gekisen: kugatsu hatsuga gōgai, 明治27年9月, Meiji 27 [1894 September] (Mapcase A5, Item 031)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, [Fukuda Kumajirō]. 出版者: [福田熊次郎].
  - 海洋嶋附近ニ敵艦ヲ打沈ム = Kaiyōtō fukin ni tekikan o shizumu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 032)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Yokoyama Ryōhachi. 出版者: 横山良八.
  - 海洋嶋決戦之圖 = Kaiyōtō kessen no zu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 033)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Published: Tokyo, Japan.
  - 錦州府方面斥候騎兵奮戦之圖 = Kinshū-fu hōmen sekkō kihei funsen no zu, [明治27/28年頃], circa Meiji 27/28 [circa 1894 or 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 034)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944.
  - 金州城撃戦 小野口工兵以爆發藥破壊金州城永安門之圖 (北上源之助・西川工兵中尉、工兵小野口徳次) = Kinshūjō gekisen, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 035)
  - 明治二十七年十一月六日金州城攻撃中工兵小野口徳治くん萬死ヲ冒シテ突進シ綿火薬ヲ以テ第一第二ノ城門ヲ破壊シ終ニ大捷ヲ致ス嗚呼勇烈ナル哉 = Meiji Nijūshichinen Jūichigatsu muika Kinshūjō kōgekichū kōhei: Meiji nijushichinen jūichigatsu muika = Meiji 27 November 6th. Onoguchi Tokuji, a soldier in Second Army, dashed with all his might and destroyed two hard gates of Kinsiu Castle by dynamite, at last, our army gained great victory. How brave he was!, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 036)
    絵師/Artist: 年方 Toshikata. Full name: 水野年方 Mizuno, Toshikata, 1866-1908. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Akiyama Takeemon. 出版者: 秋山武右衛門.
  - 金州城占領ノ圖 = Kinshūjō senryō no zu, 明治27年10月, Meiji 27 [1894 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 037)
    絵師/Artist: 揚斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉.
  - 黄海附近海軍大激戦 = Kōkai fukin Kaigun daigekisen = Naval War battle near the Yellow Sea, [明治27年頃], circa Meiji 27 [circa 1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 038)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944.
  - 黄海北海洋島附近大日本海軍大勝利 = Kōkai Hokkaiyōtō fukin Dai Nihon Kaigun daishōri, 明治27年9月, Meiji 27 [1894 September] (Mapcase A5, Item 039)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo Japan, Ozeki Iwakichi. 出版者: 臨写印刷兼発行者 尾関岩吉 日本橋区若松町十五番地.
  - 黄海之戦我松島之水兵臨死問敵艦之存否 = Kōkai no ikusa waga Matsushima no suihei shi ni nozonde tekikan no zonpi o tou = A Sailor of the Japanese Flagship Matsushima asks with His Last Breath If the Enemy Battleship Tingyuen Has Been Sunk, [明治27年頃], circa Meiji 27 [circa 1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 040)
    絵師/Artist: 清親 Kiyochika. Also known as: 小林清親 Kobayashi, Kiyochika, 1847-1915.
  - 虎山附近騎兵ヲ攻撃ス = Kozan fukin kihei o kōgeki su, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 041)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Kumajirō. 出版者: 福田熊次郎.
  - 休戦軍使 = Kyūsen gunshi, 明治20, Meiji 20 [1887] (Mapcase A5, Item 042)
  - 休戦軍使 = Kyūsen gunshi, 明治20, Meiji 20 [1887] (Mapcase A5, Item 043)
  - 休戦軍使 = Kyūsen gunshi, 明治28年6月, Meiji 28 [1895 June] (Mapcase A5, Item 044)
  - 日本兵大勝利祝宴を開く圖 = Nihon hei daishōri shukuen o hiraku zu, [明治27/28年頃], circa Meiji 27/28 [circa 1894 or 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 045)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912.
  - 日本海軍大勝利鴨緑江口海戦 = Nihon Kaigun daishōri Ōryoku kōkō kaisen, 明治27年9月26日, Meiji 27 [1894 September 26] (Mapcase A5, Item 046)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉. Geographical Subject: 鴨緑江 Yalu River
  - 日本全勝大孤山沖海戦十五ノ内第十 = Nihon zenshō Daikosan-oki kaisen jūgo no uchi jū, [明治27年頃], circa Meiji 27 [circa 1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 047)
    絵師/Artist: 幾英 Ikuhide. Also known as: 小林幾英 Kobayashi, Ikuhide; 小林英次郎 Kobayashi, Eijiro (active 1885-1898). Published: Tokyo, Japan, Suharaya Matsunari Yasutaro. 出版者: 須原屋松成保太郎. Geographical Subject: 大孤山 Dagu Mountain
  - 日清激戦帝國大勝利 = Nisshin gekisen teikoku daishōri, 明治27年8月, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 048)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Ishijima Yae. 出版者: 石島八重.
  - 日清平壌大激戦之図 = Nisshin Heijō daigekisen no zu, [明治27年頃], circa Meiji 27 [circa 1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 049)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Geographical Subject: 平壌 Pyongyang
  - 日清威海衛海戦 = Nisshin Ikaiei kaisen, 明治27年刊, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 050)
    絵師/Artist: 香朝楼 Kōchōrō. Also known as: 竹内栄久 Takeuchi, Eikyū, 4代目 国政豊斎 Kunimasa, Hōsai, IV, 三代目 歌川国貞 Utagawa Kunisada, III (1889-), 1848-1920. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Hatsujirō. 出版者: 福田初次郎. Geographical Subject: 威海衛 Weihaiwei
  - 日清開戦於成歓日本兵大勝利図 = Seikan ni oite Nisshin gekisen waga hei daishōri, 明治27年8月, Meiji 27 [1894 August] (Mapcase A5, Item 051)
    絵師/Artist: 豊洲 Hōshū. Published: Yokohama, Japan. Geographical Subject: 成歓 Seonghwan
  - 日清成観ノ陸戦 我軍大勝利我山ヲ進撃ノ図 = Nisshin Seikan no rikusen waga gun daishōri Gazan o shingeki no zu, 明治27年8月12日, Meiji 27 [1894 August 12] (Mapcase A5, Item 052)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Higuchi, Gintarō. 出版者: 樋口銀太郎. Geographical Subject: 我山 Wagayama
  - 日清戦争牛荘附近攻戦之圖 = Nisshin Sensō Gyūsō fukin kōsen no zu, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 053)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsutsumi Kichibei. 出版者: 堤吉兵衛. Geographical Subject: 牛荘 Gyūsō
  - 日清戦争威海衛ニ於我軍激戦ス = Nisshin Sensō Ikaiei ni oite waga gun gekisen su, 明治28年2月, Meiji 28 [1895 February] (Mapcase A5, Item 054)
    絵師/Artist: 年章 Toshiaki. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Fukuda Kumajirō. 出版者: 福田熊次郎. Geographical Subject: 威海衛 Weihaiwei
  - 日清戦争之内 明治廿八年一月三十日我第二軍威海衛攻撃ノ際百尺厓大激戦ハ天風雪ニシテ遂ニ是レヲ占領シ加之清国司令官戴将軍モ戦死セリト云フ = Nisshin Senso no uchi Meiji nijūhachinen ichigatsu sanjunichi Meiji nijūhachinen ichigatsu sanjūnichi waga dai nigun Ikaiei kōgeki no sai …., [明治28年頃], circa Meiji 28 [circa 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 055)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Geographical Subject: 威海衛 Weihaiwei
  - 大寺将軍全力ヲ揮テ百尺崖ヲ襲撃スル之図 = Ōdera shōgun zenryoku o furuite hyakushakugake o shūgeki suru no zu, [明治28年頃], circa Meiji 28 [circa 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 056)
    絵師/Artist: 月耕 Gekkō. Also known as: 尾形月耕 Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920. Geographical Subject: 威海衛 Weihaiwei
  - 鴨緑江以北ニ於テ我軍大勝之圖 = Ōryokukō ihoku ni oite waga gun taishō no zu, 明治27年10月, Meiji 27 [1894 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 057)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Higuchi Gintarō. 出版者: 樋口銀太郎. Geographical Subject: 鴨緑江 Yalu River, Amnok-kang
  - 旅順口附近我斥候進撃之圖 = Ryojunkō fukin waga sekkō shingeki no zu, 明治27年9月26日, Meiji 27 [1894 September 26] (Mapcase A5, Item 059)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 旅順口ニテ斥候騎兵奮戦 = Ryojunkō nite sekkō kihei funsen, 明治28年10月, Meiji 28 [1895 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 060)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 旅順口陥落之圖 = Ryojunkō kanraku no zu, [明治27/28年頃], circa Meiji 27/28 [circa 1894 or 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 061)
    絵師/Artist: 月耕 Gekkō. Also known as: 尾形月耕 Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 旅順口燈台（臺）之図 = Ryojunkō tōdai no zu, 明治27年10月10日, Meiji 27 [1894 October 10] (Mapcase A5, Item 062)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 旅順ノ山間ニ露営将士日光を拝ス図 = Ryojun no sankan ni roei shōshi nikkō o haisu zu, 明治27年12月, Meiji 27 [1894 December] (Mapcase A5, Item 063)
    絵師/Artist: 月耕 Gekkō. Also known as: 尾形月耕 Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Matsuno Yonejirō. 出版者: 松野米次郎. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 佐藤大佐 牛荘激戦ノ役聯隊旗ヲ杖ニシテ突貫ス = Satō Taisa Gyūsōjō gekisen no eki rentaiki o tsue ni shite tokkan su, 明治28年6月11日刊, Meiji 28 [1895 June 11] (Mapcase A5, Item 064)
    絵師/Artist: 月耕 Gekkō. Also known as: 尾形月耕 Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Sekiguchi Seijirō. 出版者: 関口政治郎. Geographical Subject: 牛荘城 Gyūsōjō
  - 成歓之駅ニ於テ松崎大尉勇戦ノ図 = Seikan no eki ni oite Matsuzaki Taii yūsen no zu, 明治27年8月, Meiji 27 [1894 August] (Mapcase A5, Item 065)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Sonokichi. 出版者: 長谷川園吉. Geographical Subject: 成歓 Seonghwan
  - 盛京省田庄台上捷報 = Seikyō-shō Denshōdai jō shōhō, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 066)
    絵師/Artist: 安達吟光 Adachi Ginkō. Also known as: 安達平七 Adachi, Heishichi. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助. Geographical Subject: 田庄台 Tianzhuangtai
  - 草河口附近日陣遠望満州騎兵異相出陣之圖 = Sōkakō fukin Nichijin enbō Manshū kihei isō shutsujin no zu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 067)
    絵師/Artist: 米作 Beisaku. Full name: 田口米作 Taguchi, Beisaku, 1864-1903. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Mizuno Asajirō. 出版者: 水野浅次郎. Geographical Subject: 草河口 Caohekou
  - 帝國大勝利之圖 = Teikoku daishōri no zu, 明治27年8月, Meiji 27 [1894 August] (Mapcase A5, Item 068)
    絵師/Artist: 豊原国輝 Toyohara Kuniteru. Also known as: 二代目 歌川国輝 Utagawa Kuniteru, 1830-1874. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Ishii Rokunosuke. 出版者: 石井六之助.
  - 我軍大捷牙山を陥る之図 = Waga gun taishō Gazan o ochiiru no zu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 069)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Sasaki Toyokichi. 出版者: 佐々木豊吉. Geographical Subject: 牙山 Asan
  - 我軍平壌奮戦之圖 = Waga gun Heijō funsen no zu, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 070)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Maki Kinnosuke. 出版者: 牧金之助. Geographical Subject: 平壌 Pyongyang
  - 我軍旅順口附近進撃之圖 = Waga gun Ryojunkō fukin shingeki no zu, [明治27/28年頃], circa Meiji 27/28 [circa 1894 or 1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 071)
    絵師/Artist: 小国政 Kokunimasa. Also known as: 五代目 歌川国政 Utagawa, Kunimasa, V.; 楳堂(梅堂)小国政 Baido Kokunimasa; 竹内柳蛙 Takeuchi Ryu-a, 1874-1944.Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 我軍太沾附近進撃之圖 = Waga gun Taisen fukin shingeki no zu, 明治27年10月, Meji 27 [1894 October] (Mapcase A5, Item 072)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsunashima Kamekichi. 出版者: 綱島亀吉. Geographical Subject: 太沾 Taisen
  - 我兵牙山に清兵を打敗る図 = Waga hei Gazan ni Shin hei o uchiyaburu zu, 明治27年8月, Meiji 27 [1894 August] (Mapcase A5, Item 073)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助. Geographical Subject: 牙山 Asan
  - 我兵平壌占領之圖 = Waga hei Heijō senryō no zu, [明治27年9月, Meiji 27 [1894 September] (Mapcase A5, Item 074)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Published: Tokyo, Japan, [Tsujioka Bunsuke]. 出版者: [辻岡文助]. Geographical Subject: 平壌 Pyongyang
  - 我北進軍隊清兵ヲ襲撃シテ九連城ヲ乗取ル = Waga hokushin guntai Shin hei o shūgeki shite Kurenjō o nottoru, 明治27年9月, Meiji 27 [1894 September] (Mapcase A5, Item 075)
    絵師/Artist: 桜琳Published: Tokyo, Japan, Shimizu Taigorō. 出版者: 清水泰五郎. Geographical Subject: 九連城 Jiuliancheng
  - 我二軍旅順口攻撃山路中将勇戦之圖 = Waga nigun Ryojunkō kōgeki Yamaji chūjō yūsen no zu, 明治27年3月, Meiji 27 [1894 March] (Mapcase A5, Item 076)
    絵師/Artist: 楊斎延一 Yōsai Nobukazu. Also known as: 楊斎延一 Yōsai, Nobukazu, 1872-1944. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Hasegawa Kuniyoshi. 出版者: 長谷川国吉. Geographical Subject: 旅順口 Port Arthur
  - 我斥候騎兵敵と衝突應戦の図 = Waga sekkō kihei teki to shōtotsu ōsen no zu, 明治27年9月6日, Meji 27 [1894 September 06] (Mapcase A5, Item 078)
    絵師/Artist: 楊洲周延 Yōshū Chikanobu. Also known as: 豊原周延 Toyohara Chikanobu, 楊洲 Yōshū, 橋本周延 Hashimoto Chikanobu, 橋本直義 Hashimoto Naoyoshi, 楊洲直義 Yōshū Naoyoshi, 1838-1912. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助.
  - 大孤山沖海軍之激戦 = Daikosan oki kaigun no gekisen, 明治27, Meiji 27 [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 081)
    絵師/Artist: 年英 Toshihide. Full name: 右田年英 Migita, Toshihide, 1863 or 1862-1925. Published: Tokyo, Japan, Tsujioka Bunsuke. 出版者: 辻岡文助. Geographical Subject: 大孤山 Dagu Mountain
  - 大孤山沖海軍大捷 = Daikosan oki kaigun taishō, 明治27, [Meiji 27] [1894] (Mapcase A5, Item 082)
    絵師/Artist: 清親 Kiyochika. Also known as: 小林清親 Kobayashi, Kiyochika, 1847-1915. Published: Tokyo, Japan. Geographical Subject: 大孤山 Dagu Mountain
  - 樋口大尉進撃之途次自ラ清民ノ遺児ヲ抱持スル之圖 = Higuchi Taii shingeki no toji mizukara Shinmin no iji o hōjisuru no zu = On the way to the battlefield, Captain Higuchi hold himself holds a child left by Chinese parents, 明治28, Meiji 28 [1895] (Mapcase A5, Item 108)
    絵師/Artist: 月耕 Gekkō. Also known as: 尾形月耕 Ogata, Gekkō, 1859-1920
- Series II: Russo-Japanese War Prints/日露戦争錦絵, 1904-1905